Finding aid to Alumnae Oral History Project collection CA.MS.00301
Smith College Archives
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2011), Accession 2012-A-0026
  - Group interview (Class of 1946) with Margaret Craig DeMott, Jane Hill, Rosalie Taylor Howlett, Helen Goddard, Abby Minot Gross, and Araxi Prévot, interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Abby Minot Gross, Rosalie Taylor Howlett, Jane Hill, Helen Goddard, Margaret DeMott, and Araxi Prévot discuss what it was like being at Smith during World War II, working on the farms, the fire in Dickinson House, and what it has meant to them to be Smith graduates.
    - Video interview with the Class of 1946 group
    - Transcript of interview with the Class of 1946 group (Box 3)
  - Glenna Hazeltine (Class of 1966) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Glenna Hazeltine describes why she chose to attend Smith, her reactions upon arrival, the overall campus atmosphere, her membership with the SDS, her involvement with Gold Key and The Sophian, her work as an English major, her opinion of President Mendenhall, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
    - Video interview with Glenna Hazeltine
    - Transcript of interview with Glenna Hazeltine (Box 3)
  - Deborah Heller (Class of 1961) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Deborah Heller discusses adjusting to Smith from Brooklyn, issues of diversity, the social pressures and her life after Smith, including her marriage, divorce, and coming out process, her involvement within the LGBT community, and her current work to establish an LGBTQQ alum affinity group.
    - Video interview with Deborah Heller
    - Transcript of interview with Deborah Heller (Box 3)
  - Charity Imbrie (Class of 1976) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Charity Imbrie describes her initial reaction to Smith, her involvement with choir and her work within the music department, the political and social atmosphere at Smith (particularly in regards to feminism and lesbianism), and her work within the legal field.
    - Video interview with Charity Imbrie
    - Transcript of interview with Charity Imbrie (Box 4)
  - Yvonne Johns (Class of 1961) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Yvonne Johns describes the overall campus atmosphere, the dating scene, her experiences as president of Gillett House, her work as an American Studies major, her experiences as a woman working within the Civil Rights movement, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
    - Video interview with Yvonne Johns
    - Transcript of interview with Yvonne Johns (Box 4)
  - Sheryl King (Class of 1971) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Sheryl King discusses what it was like being Southern at Smith during the late 1960s/early 70s, the overall campus atmosphere (particularly in regards to activism and feminism), and her experiences after Smith.
    - Video interview with Sheryl King
    - Transcript of interview with Sheryl King (Box 4)
  - Phyllis (Patti) Klein (Class of 1961) interviewed by Grace Martin, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    This interview is available for research. Online access must be made anonymous.
    In this oral history, Phyllis "Patti" Klein describes the overall campus atmosphere, her work in the history, art history, and English departments, and her life after Smith.
    - Video interview with Phyllis "Patti" Klein
    - Transcript of interview with Phyllis "Patti" Klein (Box 4)
  - Marilyn Johnson Martin (Class of 1957) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Marilyn Johnston Martin discusses living in Lawrence House, her social life, her relationship with Sylvia Plath, issues of class, her decision to leave after her sophomore year, and her life after Smith.
    - Video interview with Marilyn Johnson Martin
    - Transcript of interview with Marilyn Johnson Martin (Box 4)
  - Karen Lewis McClure (Class of 1961) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 19; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Karen McClure describes the overall campus atmosphere, her involvement in sports, her work as a sociology major, issues of diversity, the dating scene, her experiences living in Wesley House, and what it feels like to be back at Smith.
    - Video interview with Karen Lewis McClure
    - Transcript of interview with Karen Lewis McClure (Box 4)
  - Jean Bradley Mooney (Class of 1956) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Jean Mooney discusses her work as an Education major, issues of diversity and class on campus, and her career in education.
    - Video interview with Jean Bradley Mooney
    - Transcript of interview with Jean Bradley Mooney (Box 4)
  - Marilyn Carlson Nelson (Class of 1961) interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Marilyn Carlson Nelson describes why she decided to attend Smith, her experiences studying abroad in Geneva, her work within the theater and dance departments, her experiences working in the business world and as CEO of the Nelson Group, one of the largest privately held companies in the world, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
  - Laura Pires-Hester (Class of 1961) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Laura Pires-Hester describes how she decided to attend Smith, what the overall campus atmosphere was like, her experiences living in Albright House, issues of race and class, the beginning of the Civil Rights Movement, her work to increase the racial diversity on campus, her life and work after Smith, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
    - Video interview with Laura Pires-Hester
    - Transcript of interview with Laura Pires-Hester (Box 4)
  - Araxi Prévot (Class of 1946) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Araxi Prévot discusses being at Smith during World War II, working on the community farms, her experiences living in Cushing House and the French House, attending a summer session at Smith, her life after Smith, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
    - Video interview with Alexi Prévot
    - Transcript of interview with Alexi Prévot (Box 4)
  - Topsy Siderowf (Class of 1961) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Topsy Siderowf discusses the overall campus atmosphere, her work as a history major, the dating scene, the beginning of the Civil Rights Movement, her interactions with Sylvia Plath, and her work at Golf Digest.
    - Video interview with Topsy Siderowf
    - Transcript of interview with Topsy Siderowf (Box 4)
  - Joyce Spencer (Class of 1961) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Joyce Spencer describes the overall campus atmosphere, her experiences singing in the choir, issues of race, ethnicity, and religion, and her life after Smith.
  - Nell Cochrane Taylor (Class of 1951) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 19; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Nell Cochrane Taylor discusses her experiences living in Lawrence House, her various roles of leadership on campus, issues of race and class, campus reactions to the Vietnam War, her position on the Board of Counselors and Board of Trustees, her experience receiving the John M. Greere award, her work with the Committee on African-American Studies, and her life after Smith.
    - Video interview with Nell Cochrane Taylor
    - Transcript of interview with Nell Cochrane Taylor (Box 4)
  - Susan Warner Thoresen (Class of 1966) interviewed by Grace Martin, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Sue Thoresen describes why she chose to attend Smith, the overall campus atmosphere, her experiences singing in the choir and glee club, the social changes that occurred at Smith during her time there, campus reactions to the Vietnam War, and her life after Smith.
    - Video interview with Susan Warner Thoresen
    - Transcript of interview with Susan Warner Thoresen (Box 4)
  - Janet Smith Walker interviewed by Olivia Mandica-Hart, 2011 May 20; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Janet Walker discusses what a Smith education has meant to her, her work as a history major, her experiences living in Gardiner House, issues of diversity, and describes a typical Smith student during the late 1950s.
    - Video with Janet Smith Walker
    - Transcript of interview with Janet Smith Walker (Box 4)
  - Kit Wang (Class of 1981) interviewed by Sarah Dunn, 2011 May 21; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Kit Wang describes the overall campus atmosphere (especially in regards to lesbianism, homophobia, and race), her experiences living in Hubbard House and Hover House, her work as a biochemistry major, her participation in the first national gay rights march on Washington, her involvement with the Lesbian Alliance, her experiences in seminary, and current work as an Episcopal priest.
    - Video interview with Kit Wang
    - Transcript of interview with Kit Wang (Box 4)
  - Eleanor C. Woods (Class of 1961) interviewed by Bethy Williams, 2011 May 19; 1 oral histories (transcript and DVD)
    In this oral history, Eleanor Woods describes her experiences playing in the orchestra, her continuing involvement with music, the dating scene at Smith, issues of racial diversity, the alumnae reaction to the Newton Arvin controversy, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
  - Original videotapes and preservation master DVDs, 2011; 1 boxes (miniDV tapes) (Box 5)
    Original av materials are restricted; digital copies are available for research
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2012), Accession 2012-A-0026
  - Edith Bershadsky (Class of 1977) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 26; Bershadsky, Class of 1977; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Edith Bershadsky describes her experiences living in Sessions House, specifically her experience dining with the male exchange students, the tradition of tea, being a feminist, and the strong friendships she formed at Smith.
    - Transcript of interview with Edith Bershadsky (Box 6)
  - Eefje Blankevoort (AMS 2004) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history Eefje Blankevoort compares the education system at Smith with her experiences in the Netherlands, discusses the new perspectives she received at Smith, her experiences in Iran before coming to Smith, and her surprise that the Iraq War was so ignored in the United States.
    - Video interview with Eefje Blankevoort
    - Transcript of interview with Eefje Blankevoort (Box 6)
  - Roberta Walsh Boylan (Class of 1962) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 26; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Roberta Walsh Boylan describes coming to Smith from Montana, living in Gillett house, campaigning for laxer social rules, moving to San Francisco after graduation with Mary Ann Savage Habib, going to Law School, and being the first woman at University of Montana Law School.
    - Video interview with Roberta Walsh Boylan
    - Transcript of interview with Roberta Walsh Boylan (Box 6)
  - Ruth Cooper (Class of 1957) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 26; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Ruth Cooper describes going to Smith in the mid-1950s and the social regulations that entailed, working hard academically, traditions like Ivy Day and after dinner coffee, and how Smith had changed when her daughter attended in the 1980s.
    - Video interview with Ruth Cooper
    - Transcript of interview with Ruth Cooper (Box 6)
  - Patricia Cunningham (Class of 1947) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    This interview is available for research only for members of the Smith College community.
    In this oral history, Patricia Cunningham describes living in Comstock, studying abroad in Mexico, focusing on her studies rather than on dating, feeling as though women should be able to do anything and being gratified when feminism began developing a few years after she graduated from Smith. Lastly, she describes working in France and her experiences in the Foreign Service.
    - Video interview with Patricia Cunningham
    - Transcript of interview with Patricia Cunningham (Box 6)
  - Nancy Davis (Class of 1982) interviewed by Kayla Ginsburg, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Nancy Davis describes falling in love with Smith and the importance of house community to her experience. She talks about racial dynamics on campus, her participation in the Bridge program, student activism, feminism, the changes she has seen at Smith and her experience as a class officer for her reunion.
    - Video interview with Nancy Davis
    - Transcript of interview with Nancy Davis (Box 6)
  - Jo Deutsch (Class of 1982) interviewed by Kayla Ginsburg, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history Jo Deutsch discusses her house community in Baldwin House, the Northampton feminist and lesbian communities, President Conway, and her first relationship with a woman at the end of her senior year. She touches upon her work as a lobbyist for 27 years and her current position at Freedom to Marry.
    - Video interview with Jo Deutsch
    - Transcript of interview with Jo Deutsch (Box 6)
  - Anne Devaney (Class of 1977) interviewed by Vivian Andreani, 2012 May 26; Devaney, Anne; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Anne Devaney describes being at Smith for its' Centennial, living in Wilder, Washburn, and Lawrence and the house traditions she remembers, the struggle for funding for the lesbian organization Sophia's Sisters, being the only white student in an African American literature class, the excitement and happiness around President Conway's appointment, her experiences as head of Recreation Council, and her career after Smith in student services and human resources.
    - Video interview with Anne Devaney
    - Transcript of interview with Anne Devaney (Box 6)
  - Paula Duffy (Class of 1967) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history Paula "Polly" Duffy discusses how her love of the French language drew her to Smith with the promise of the JYA Paris program. She describes her first impressions at Smith, the house community she found in Hubbard House, and her experiences as someone coming from a family with a lower income than most Smithies. She goes on to talk about the dating scene and her participation as the vocalist in the first female, white, rock and roll group on campus, called the RhymeStones. She ends by discussing the opportunities afforded to her through the Smith network.
    - Video interview with Paula Duffy
    - Transcript of interview with Paula Duffy (Box 6)
  - Natalie Field (Class of 1957) interviewed by Vivian Andreani, 2012 May 26; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Natalie Field described the tradition of singing at Smith at events like Rally Day and the senior show, and sang several Smith songs. She also describes going to chapel every Wednesday, watching TV in Davis, the Kingsmen, being at Smith during the space race, and house social regulations. Throughout, Field laments the loss of Smith traditions.
    - Video interview with Natalie Field
    - Transcript of interview with Natalie Field (Box 6)
  - Magaret Freeman (AMS 1963) interviewed by Kayla Ginsburg, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Margaret Freeman describes her transition from University of Manchester, England to Smith College as one of the first group of the AMS Diploma Scholars. She describes the social life in Talbot House, the cultural differences, her surprise at the quality of Smith food and the practice of knitting in classes, and the ways Smith affected her life, particularly her intellectual confidence.
    - Video interview with Margaret Freeman
    - Transcript of interview with Margaret Freeman (Box 6)
  - Marcy Friedman (Class of 1972) interviewed by Kayla Ginsburg, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Marcy Friedman discusses her initial impression of Smith as conservative, her activism protesting the Vietnam War, and the changes she saw during her time at Smith. She comments on the racial dynamics and the silence surrounding lesbianism and same-sex relationships. She describes graduating as an "emerging radical second wave feminist," and her current position as a New York Supreme Court Justice.
    - Video interview with Marcy Friedman
    - Transcript of interview with Marcy Friedman (Box 6)
  - Marlene Futterman (Class of 1958) interviewed by Vivian Andreani, 2012 May 26; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Marlene Futterman describes choosing Smith because of its study abroad programs, studying in Geneva and subsequently going into the Foreign Service after graduating, and gaining confidence at Smith.
    - Video interview with Marlene Futterman
    - Transcript of interview with Marlene Futterman (Box 6)
  - Sandra Gleason (Class of 1967) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 26; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Sandra Gleason describes becoming an economics major, coming from a military family, living in Capen House, her housemothers, the traditions of mountain day and Rally day, her experience as a research assistant, the atmosphere of acceptance and open-mindedness at Smith, the benefits of the women's college experience, and her career in the academic world.
    - Video interview with Sandra Gleason
    - Transcript of interview with Sandra Gleason (Box 6)
  - Mary Ann Savage Habib (Class of 1962) interviewed by Kayla Ginsburg, 2012 May 26; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Mary Ann Savage Habib describes struggling through her first year, the dating scene, seeing Martin Luther King Jr. speak at Helen Hills Chapel, her decision to move to California after graduating, and working at the National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections.
    - Video interview with Mary Ann Savage Habib
    - Transcript of interview with Mary Ann Savage Habib (Box 6)
  - Danielle Hussey (Class of 2002) interviewed by Vivian Andreani, 2012 May 24; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Danielle Hussey describes how she found out about Smith from a high school English teacher, how she transferred from University of Vermont after her freshman year, her house community in Morrow House, the atmosphere of intellectual rigor, her participation in Peer Sexuality Educators (PSE) and other clubs, how the campus reacted to 9/11, and the importance of Ruth Simmons to her and the Smith Community in general.
    - Video interview with Danielle Hussey
    - Transcript of interview with Danielle Hussey (Box 6)
  - Ellen Kipnis Kanner (Class of 1967) interviewed by Kayla Ginsburg, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Ellen Kipnis Kanner describes her experience at Smith as a Jewish student, her study abroad in Spain, and a love of Smith College that continues years later.
    - Video interview with Ellen Kipnis Kanner
    - Transcript of interview with Ellen Kipnis Kanner (Box 6)
  - Brenda Lewis (Class of 1967) interviewed by Vivian Andreani, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Brenda Lewis describes her class as the last traditional class, comments upon the changes that took place during her tenure at Smith, and discusses her success in the world of business after graduating.
    - Video interview with Brenda Lewis
    - Transcript of interview with Brenda Lewis (Box 7)
  - Jerri Pantages Long (Class of 1967) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this oral history, Jerri Pantages Long describes arriving at Smith from California, living in Parson for one year and then Tenney House for three years. She talks about Mountain Day and May Day traditions and the importance of a women's school.
    - Video interview with Jerri Pantages Long
    - Transcript of interview with Jerri Pantages Long (Box 7)
  - Sue Marcoux (Class of 1982) interviewed by Vivian Andreani, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories
    In this oral history, Susan Marcoux describes living in Albright House for two years, going abroad in Germany, living in Hover House for her senior year, the lesbian scene at Smith, her work with Lesbian Alliance, and building an intellectual Smith community in San Francisco after graduating.
    - Video interview with Sue Marcoux
    - Transcript of interview with Sue Marcoux (Box 7)
  - Lucille Nawara (Class of 1962) interviewed by Vivian Andreani, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories
    In this oral history, Lucille Nawara describes coming to Smith as a legacy student, her fear of posture pictures, coming from an artistic family and deciding to study art and music at Smith, feeling out of place in high school but comfortable at Smith, struggling through astronomy class, living in Tenney House and having President Mendenhall over for dinner, traditions like Mountain Day and regulations in the houses, the positive aspects of taking phys ed, and the confidence and analytical skills that Smith gave her as she continued on as an art professor and landscape designer.
    - Video interview with Lucille Nawara
    - Transcript of interview with Lucille Nawara (Box 7)
  - Francie Garber Pepper (Class of 1962) interviewed by Kayla Ginsburg, 2012 May 24; 1 oral histories
    In this oral history, Francie Pepper describes shattering her high school teacher's expectations by not only going to Smith but succeeding as well. She discusses coming from a long line of strong women, participating in sports while at Smith, studying abroad in Madrid, going to secretarial school and using her Spanish to get top jobs, raising money for the YWCA, and working on social issues like birth control, domestic violence, and trafficking.
    Pepper, Frances Garber, Class of 1962
    - Video interview with Francie Garber Pepper
    - Transcript of interview with Francie Garber Pepper (Box 7)
  - Paula Roberts (Class of 1967) interviewed by Vivian Andreani, 2012 May 25; 1 oral histories
    In this oral history, Paula Roberts discusses her political consciousness starting at a young age, and how it grew and developed at Smith. She describes interning with Congressman Conte and Project Cornerstone, an experience that developed her understanding of racism. After leaving Smith, she talks about becoming a welfare caseworker and going to Law school.
    - Video interview with Paula Roberts
    - Transcript of interview with Paula Roberts (Box 7)
  - Monica Ricci Sargentini (AMS 1987) interviewed by Kirby Vasquez, 2012 May 24; 1 oral histories